# Thapelo Radebe

Johannesburg Metropolitan Area



vivathapelo@gmail.com



0649047642



linkedin.com/in/thapeloradebe

# **Summary**

Thapelo Radebe is a BCom Business Management Graduate from the University of Pretoria and I'm currently working as a Senior Software Engineer at Vaxowave while furthering my academics at Wits Business School with a Postgraduate Diploma in Business Administration. I have 9 years worth of IT knowledge and skills that come in handy when solving business problems.

# **Experience**

# Senior Software Engineer

**Emendis BV** 

Nov 2022 - Jan 2023 (3 months)

# Full Stack Engineer (Analyst)

**BCB** Group

Dec 2021 - Dec 2022 (1 year 1 month)

Working with cross functional teams, both development and Product owners to improve products and add new features.

Handled a project for delivering automatic account creation of multi currency accounts to improve account creation time by about 40%

Worked daily on fixing bugs based on the severity of the bug on day-to-day business.

Worked closely with Quality Assurance Engineer to make sure that we deliver quality solutions.

Worked closely with a Business Analyst on communicating and polishing requirements so that they are deliverable and they make sense.

Using Google Cloud tools to extend development and also monitor the applications.

Working on Full stack features that span about 5 services for an application.

Working with the Support Team to fix issues and also improve the product based of clients communication.

# **W** Back End Developer

Vaxowave

May 2021 - Oct 2021 (6 months)

Technical analysis to understand requirements and dependencies.

Developing secure DotNet Core MVC API endpoints with C#.

Developing secure Spring Framework API endpoints with Kotlin.

Collaborating with different teams to fix dependencies.

Working together with Business Analysts to map out requirements and dependencies with what exists and what could be delivered.

Working with Project Managers for Sprint planning and estimating workload for each individual sprints.

# 🎅 Senior Software Engineer

### The Sun Exchange

Sep 2020 - Mar 2021 (7 months)

Doing primary and also secondary technical support duties from Trello tickets using Postgres scripts.

Find bugs/issues to report them for discussion on using Trello cards.

Code and debug VueJs, NodeJs, Postgres, GraphQL, REST, BootStrap applications

Write and run Unit-Tests and Integration-Tests for my code or for existing code that is missing them.

Working closely with Quality Assurance Engineers(Testers) for code walk-throughs and for helping them test in QA.

Deploying and running docker containers to run the Development environment.

Deploy and running Development, QA and Production Environments.

Self-assigning tasks/issues from the Dev-Backlog and move them to code-review when done.

Use Chrome/Firefox developer tools to debug our web application even for mobile devices.

Remove old code, add sanity checks and insure idempotency.

Do code-reviews of other developers, add comments and fix conflicts on Gitlab.

Using JavaScript and Typescript as my primary development languages.

# Senior Software Engineer

### iTeamPay

Jul 2020 - Aug 2020 (2 months)

Designing applications for making payments easier and secure.

Modernizing ITeampPay's web applications using Angular 10, Bootstrap 4 and Firebase.

Integrating company's payment gateway internally and with external clients.

Integrating 3rd party Binary Trading APIs with an Angular Web Application.

Building and Deploy JAVA EE Spring Backend and Web Services

### Note: Information Technology Consultant

Mbulase Group (Pty) Ltd

Apr 2019 - Jun 2020 (1 year 3 months)

Web development using JavaScript and PHP stack, BootStrap.

Doing data visualization with Oracle DV and Tableau

Building and Deploy JAVA EE Spring Backend and Web Services

Regularly meeting with clients and 3rd party software suppliers to architect solutions

Assisting the Team with IT resourcing throughout the Data Management Lifecycle

Deploying and managing a Windows server and also installing enterprise software for demos

Flutter cross-platform development for Android, iOS, Desktop and Web

Utilising Jira Core for issue logging, tracking and reporting

Utilising Codemagic CI/CD for flutter projects

Using Github as a GIT repository for internal projects

Use Business Intelligence and Analytics(BI&A) to explain clients' past business events and predict their future events.

# Mobile Full Stack Developer

KTR Consulting (Pty) Ltd

Nov 2013 - Nov 2018 (5 years 1 month)

Business Development - Finding clients online and through my network

Account Management - Acquiring and Retention of clients through a Client Relationship Management

Mobile Application Development - Designing and Developing Android, Mobile Web and Flutter Application

Web Application Development - Designing and Developing Websites and Backend Web Applications using CSS, JQUERY, PHP, CodeIngitor, BootStrap and JAVA EE Spring

Brand Strategy - Assisted Small Business in Design their corporate design assets and develop a social media strategy



### Web Developer

Mar 2012 - Sep 2012 (7 months)

Business Development - Finding clients online and through my network

Account Management - Acquiring and Retention of clients through a Client Relationship Management Web Application Development - Designing and Developing Websites and Backend Web Applications using CSS, JQUERY, PHP, BootStrap and Code Ignitor

Regularly meeting with clients through the design and development process

# **∧** Software Developer

Awaken VR

Jun 2011 - Feb 2012 (9 months)

Mobile Application Development - Designing and Developing Android, Mobile Web and Flutter Application

Web Application Development - Designing and Developing Websites and Backend Web Applications using CSS, JQUERY, PHP and Code Ignitor

Brand Activations of Big International Brands using Augmented Reality and Virtual Reality tools

: Contract ended

### **Education**



### University of Pretoria/Universiteit van Pretoria

Bachelor of Commerce (BCom), Business Management

2015 - 2019

Majored in:

**Business Management** 

International Business

Marketing Management



### University of the Witwatersrand (Incomplete)

Bachelor of Science - BS (Incomplete), Mathematics and Computer Science (Incomplete)

2007 - 2010

Incomplete



### Reunert College

College, Mathematics, Physics 2006 - 2006

### **Licenses & Certifications**

- International Programming Contest Certificate of Achievement ICPC International Collegiate Programming Contest
- Computer Literacy and Microsoft Office The Independent Institute of Education CCOMP12094377
- in Blockchain Basics LinkedIn
- AWS Cloud Computing AWS Educate Digital Certificate Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Software Development Engineer AWS Educate Digital Certificate Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- GIT Training Simplilearn 2864733
- Getting started with NodeJS Simplilearn 2873432
- ReactJS for beginners Simplilearn 2884672
- Getting Started with Docker Simplilearn 3010240
- in Programming Foundations: Fundamentals LinkedIn
- in Programming Foundations: Databases LinkedIn
- in Succeeding in Web Development: Full Stack and Front End LinkedIn
- HTML Essential Training LinkedIn
- in CSS Essential Training LinkedIn

### Skills

Web Development • Java • Android Development • Software Development • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • Cloud Computing • JavaScript • PHP • jQuery • CSS

# **Honors & Awards**

Certificate of Achievement - ICPC - ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest Apr 2009